classkick.com 2018-06-29

# Privacy | Classkick

Classkick’s mission is to ensure that students everywhere get the help they need at the moment they need it. We’re honored to partner with teachers and educators around the world who trust Classkick to do that every day. Ensuring your privacy is important to us in maintaining that trust. 

This Privacy Policy explains:

  * What information Classkick collects and why,

  * How we use and share that information,

  * The choices you have for accessing, updating and deleting information.

This policy applies to all products and services offered by Classwork Co. (“Classkick,” “we,” “us,” “our,” and our subsidiaries or affiliates).

Personal information is any information you provide to us that personally identifies you, like your name or email address, or other information which could be reasonably linked to such identifying information by us. We will only collect, use, and share your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This policy applies whether you use Classkick through [classkick.com](http://classkick.com/) (the “Classkick Website”), our mobile applications (the “Classkick Apps”), or any of our other products or services that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Service”). Your use of our Site, Apps, or Services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our [Terms of Service](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service), including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. The [Terms of Service](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service) are incorporated by reference into this Policy. In addition, this Privacy Policy also covers Classkick's treatment of any personal information about our users that our partners or other services might share with us, for example responses to a teacher survey collected through Google Forms.

This policy does not apply to websites or services or practices of companies that Classkick doesn’t own or control, such as third party services you might access through links or other features (e.g., social media buttons) on the Service. These other services have their own privacy policies, and we encourage you to review them before providing them with personal information.

By using the Service, you acknowledge that you accept and agree to this Privacy Policy.

### What is Classkick?

Classkick is a platform that helps teachers provide feedback to students in real-time. Teachers use Classkick to monitor student work and give students feedback while working. They use the [Classkick App](https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/classkick/id909904332?mt=8) or the [Classkick Website](http://app.classkick.com/) \- if multiple devices are used, they will all sync with each other.

Students access Classkick using a code provided by their teacher. If a student’s teacher elects to utilize Classkick, the student (without needing to sign up for a Classkick student account) may draw, type, take photos, add audio, or links (which may contain personal information) which will be collected by Classkick. The teacher or school will be responsible for obtaining any necessary parental consent under our [COPPA Privacy Policy](http://classkick.com/coppa-privacy-policy). 

A teacher or school may ask that a student create a dedicated account on Classkick. Students cannot create an account by themselves, but must be invited to Classkick by a teacher or school administrator; if they are under 13, they will need to have parental consent or notice in order to access their account. When students set up a Classkick account, they create a unique username and password, and/or sign in using a third party sign-in service, such as their Google account.

Parents may also access Classkick using a code provided by their student’s teacher, or through an email invitation directly from the student or teacher containing the code. 

More information on how the Service operates is located [here](http://classkick.com/support) and your participation and use of the Service is governed by our [Terms of Service](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service) (“[Terms](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service)”).

### How does Classkick protect children’s personal information?

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. This is why we have signed the [Student Privacy Pledge](https://studentprivacypledge.org/) and work with teachers and schools to ensure we are compliant with [COPPA](https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/rules/rulemaking-regulatory-reform-proceedings/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule). COPPA protects the online privacy of children under the age of 13 (“child” or “children”); for more information about COPPA and protecting children’s online privacy, please visit our [COPPA Privacy Policy](http://classkick.com/coppa-privacy-policy).

### What information does Classkick collect from children, and how is it used?

Classkick collects the minimal amount of information from students necessary to work or create accounts on our Service. Where students have permission to use Classkick, we collect their name, unique username or email address, password, and code provided by their teacher to connect with a class. This information may be entered by a teacher or the student or populated from the student’s account with a third party sign-in service, such as their Google account.

If a student’s school or teacher elects to utilize Classkick, the student (without needing to sign up for a Classkick student account) may draw, type, take photos, add audio, and links (which may contain personal information) which will be collected by Classkick. The teacher or school will be responsible for obtaining any necessary parental consent under COPPA.

In addition to the information listed above, we automatically collect some information from any use of our Service as set forth in the "Information collected automatically" section.

We use this information to provide the Service to the child, for security and safety purposes, as required by law, or to enforce our [Terms](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service). We will not require children to provide more personal information than is reasonably necessary in order to participate in the Service. If we discover that we have collected information from a child in a manner inconsistent with COPPA, we will take appropriate steps to either delete the information, or immediately seek the parent’s consent for that collection. We do not disclose any personal information about children to third parties, except to service providers necessary to provide the Service, as required by law, or to protect the security of the Service or other users. Information collected from students (including personal information and information collected automatically) is never used or disclosed for third party advertising or for any first- or third-party behaviorally targeted advertising, and children’s personal information is never sold or rented to anyone, including marketers or advertisers.

We also receive from the child’s teacher whatever name he or she has provided, and the feedback assigned by that teacher. Teachers can choose to provide full names for students (e.g., first name and last name) when setting up their class; they can also only provide non-identifying information (e.g., just first name, initials, or seat numbers). 

We reserve the right to terminate student accounts that have not been accessed for a period of more than one year, unless we are required by law to retain it, need it to ensure the security of our community or our Service, or to enforce our [Terms](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service). 

### Push Notifications

Classkick may send push notifications to students - for example, letting them know when they have received feedback from their teacher. If you are a student or a parent of a child and no longer want these communications to be sent, please either turn off the push notifications on your device, or contact us at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com).

### What Children’s Information is Visible to Others?

If a teacher utilizes the Student Helpers feature in Classkick, other students may view the drawings, text, images, audio, or links added by other students in Classkick. Teachers may share their classes, including student work and feedback provided, with other teachers or school leaders in their school. If the teacher chooses to display Classkick through projecting to a whiteboard, for example, students physically present in that classroom may see other students’ names, work, and feedback. Teachers can choose not to utilize Classkick in any of these ways.

### Parental Choices

If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child who has created a Classkick account and you were not informed by your child’s teacher or school (as per COPPA), you can email us at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com) to have that child’s account deleted.

Any parents that want copies of their children’s personal information that we may have stored can contact us by sending an email to [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com). At any time, parents can refuse to permit us to collect further personal information from their children, and can request that we delete the personal information we have collected from their child by contacting us at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com). Please keep in mind that deleting records may require us to terminate the account in question. Also remember that before we can share the information with you, or delete it per your request, we will need to verify your identity, for example by requiring that you provide acceptable forms of personal identification.

### What information does Classkick collect?

We collect two types of information about you:

  1. information that you voluntarily provide us by using the Classkick Service (described below under "Information you provide to us") and

  2. information collected automatically as result of your use of the Service (described below under “Information collected automatically”). 

The types and amounts of information collected will vary depending on whether the user is a teacher, school leader, parent, or student (e.g. we collect minimal information from students) and how they use Classkick (e.g. if teachers join their school, we may need to collect school information).

### Information you provide to us

We describe the information collected from students under 13 in the section above; for other users, we collect and store the following types of information:

  * To create a Classkick account as a teacher, school leader, or parent, you may be asked to provide some basic information such as your first and last name, email address, and password. If you create a Classkick account as a student, you will be asked to enter the code you have been given by your teacher (students are unable to sign up for the Service without this), along with your name, a unique username, and a password. Students may also sign in using a third party sign-in service, such as their Google account.

  * As a teacher or school leader, you can invite your students’ parents to join the Service, for example by providing their email address within Classkick. As a parent, school leader, or teacher you can also invite others to join the Service by utilizing your own native mobile application functionality through the Classkick App, for example by email or sharing via Facebook or Twitter. We will collect and store the email addresses you provide with these requests, and will also treat this as personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If these individuals would like to request deletion of their information, they may contact us directly at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com).

  * As a teacher or school leader, you can provide customized feedback. If the teacher chooses to display student work to class, other students in the class may be able to see each other’s feedback.

  * When you choose to provide us with your personal information through the Service in some other manner (e.g., when you send us an email asking a question, submit a support request, participate in a video testimonial about our Service, or choose to participate in any research efforts with Classkick to improve the Service), we collect and store the information to tailor the Service for you, and to help the Service work better for you.

Our use of the information above is described below in the “How does Classkick use the information it collects” section.

### Information collected automatically

We (or our service providers) may automatically receive and log information on our server from your browser or your device when you use the Service. If you use Classkick on different devices, we may link the information we collect from those different devices to help us provide a consistent Service across your different devices. If we do combine any automatically-collected information with personal information, we will treat the combined information as personal information, and it will be protected as per this Privacy Policy.

The technologies and information we automatically collect include:

  * We (or our service providers) may use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit our Service. We may use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Site, App, or Services. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site and Services, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities at our Site and Service. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you.

  * Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function.

  * We may also engage third parties, such as Google Analytics and Mixpanel, to track and analyze data from our Site, App, or Services and to evaluate usage of our Site and our App. We use the data collected by such third parties to help us administer and improve the quality of our Site, App, and Services, to analyze Site and App usage, and to help us improve our Services, performance, and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services. These third parties are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf, except to help us conduct and improve our business. We do not share personal information with these third parties.

  * We collect device-specific information such as your operating system, hardware version, device settings, file and software names and types, battery and signal strength, and device identifiers. This helps us measure how the Service is performing, improve Classkick for you on your particular device, and send you push notifications if you’ve opted in to receive them.

  * When you use our Service, we automatically collect and store certain information in our server logs. This information helps us make decisions about what we should work on next. Examples include things like:

    * Details of how you used our service, such as your activity on the Service, and the frequency and duration of your visits to the Classkick Website or Classkick App

    * IP Address

    * Device event information such as crashes, system activity, hardware settings, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and referral URL

  * Our Site, App, and Services may contain links to third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third-party websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third-party websites.

### How does Classkick use the information it collects?

First and foremost, you should know that Classkick does not sell or rent any of your, or your child’s, personal information to any third party for any purpose - including for advertising or marketing purposes. Targeted advertising is not permitted on Classkick. We use the information we collect from you to provide you with the best Classkick experience. More specifically, this information is used:

  * To provide our Services, to communicate with teacher users about your use of our Services, to respond to inquiries, and for other customer service purposes.

  * To provide students and teachers with information and reports about student performance and use of the Site, App, and Services.

  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to users, to offer personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using the Site, App, or Services.

  * For marketing and promotional purposes. We may use information collected from teacher users, to send such users you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact such users about products or information we think may be of interest. We will not send marketing or promotional materials to student users.

  * To better understand how users access and use our Site, App, and Services, on an aggregated or de-identified basis, in order to improve our Site, App, and Services and respond to user desires and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes.

We use automatically collected information (described in the "Information collected automatically" section above) to provide and support our Service, and for the additional uses described in this section of our Privacy Policy.

### Will Classkick share any information it collects?

Classkick does not sell or rent personal information to any third party for any purpose. Furthermore, we do not share personal information with any third parties except in the limited circumstances described in this Privacy Policy:

  * If you are a teacher, school leader, or a parent, you may choose to share information or content through the Service with other Classkick teachers, school leaders, or parents. Please keep in mind that information (including personal Information or children's personal information) or content that you voluntarily disclose to others - including to other Classkick users you interact with through the Service - can be viewed, copied, stored, and used by the people you share it with. We cannot control the actions of people with whom you choose to share information.

  * When, as a teacher, school leader, or parent, you use third-party apps, websites or other services that use, or are integrated with, our Service, they may receive information about what you post or share. For example, when you invite others via Facebook or Twitter, these services receive the information that you share through this functionality, and information that you are sharing from Classkick. Information collected by these apps, websites or integrated services is subject to their own terms and policies.

  * Targeted advertising is not permitted on Classkick. We do work with vendors, service providers, and other partners to help us provide the Service by performing tasks on our behalf. We may need to share or provide information (including personal information) to them to help them perform these business functions, for example sending emails on our behalf, database management services, database hosting, providing customer support software, and security. Generally, these service providers do not have the right to use your personal information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. Additionally, these service providers must adhere to confidentiality and security obligations in a way that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

  * We post testimonials on our Service which may contain personal information such as the name, photo and/or a video of the individual in the testimonial. We obtain the individual’s consent in advance to ensure we have permission to post this content publicly. To request removal of your personal information from our testimonials, please contact us at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com).

  * We use analytics services, including mobile analytics software, to help us understand and improve how the Service is being used. These services may collect, store and use information in order to help us understand things like how often you use the Service, the events that occur within the application, usage, performance data, and from where the application was downloaded.

  * We may share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information publicly, including with users, partners or the press in order to, for example, demonstrate how Classkick is used, spot industry trends, or to provide marketing materials for Classkick. Any aggregated information shared this way will not contain any personal information.

  * We may disclose personal information if we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary to comply with the law, such as complying with a subpoena or other legal process. We may need to disclose personal information where, in good faith, we think it is necessary to to protect the rights, property, or safety of Classkick, our employees, our community, or others, or to prevent violations of our our Terms of Service or other agreements. This includes, without limitation, exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection or responding to government requests.

  * Over time, Classkick may grow and reorganize. We may share your personal information with affiliates such as a parent company, subsidiaries, joint venture partners or other companies that we control or that are under common control with us, in which case we will require those companies to agree to use your personal information in a way that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

  * In the event that all or a portion of Classkick or its assets are acquired by or merged with a third party, personal information that we have collected from users would be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by that third party. This Privacy Policy will continue to apply to your information, and any acquirer would only be able to handle your personal information as per this policy (unless you give consent to a new policy). We will provide you with notice of an acquisition within thirty (30) days following the completion of such a transaction, by posting on our homepage, or by email to your email address that you provided to us. If you do not consent to the use of your personal information by such a successor company, you may request its deletion from the company. 

  * In the unlikely event that Classkick goes out of business, or files for bankruptcy, we will protect your personal information, and will not sell it to any third party.

Other than the cases above, we won’t disclose your personal information for any purpose unless you consent to it. Additionally, as discussed above, we will never sell or rent your personal information to advertisers or other third parties.

### How does Classkick protect and secure my information?

Your Classkick account is protected by a password. You can help us protect against unauthorized access to your account by keeping your password secret at all times. 

The security of your personal information is important to us. We work hard to protect our community, and we maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect against unauthorized use, disclosure of or access to personal information. In particular:

  * Our engineering team is dedicated to keeping your personal information secure

  * We continually develop and implement features to keep your personal information safe - for example, when you enter any information anywhere on the Service, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL/TLS) by default

  * We ensure passwords are stored and transferred securely using encryption and salted hashing

Although we make concerted good faith efforts to maintain the security of personal information, and we work hard to ensure the integrity and security of our systems, no practices are 100% immune, and we can’t guarantee the security of information. Outages, attacks, human error, system failure, unauthorized use or other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time. If we learn of a security breach, we will attempt to notify you electronically (subject to any applicable laws) so that you can take appropriate protective steps; for example, we may post a notice on our homepage ([classkick.com](http://classkick.com/)) or elsewhere on the Service, and may send email to you at the email address you have provided to us. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.

### Can I opt-out of providing information?

You can always decline to share personal information with us, or even block all cookies. However, it’s important to remember that many of Classkick’s features may not be accessible, or may not function properly.

### How can I access and manage my personal information?

Classkick aims to provide you with easy access to any personal information we have collected about you. If that information is incorrect, we give you easy ways to update it, or to delete it, unless we have to keep that information for legitimate business (e.g., we need at least an email address for your account) or legal purposes.

  * Upon request, Classkick will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information, and, if you are a user of Classkick, you may request access to all your personal information we have on file by contacting us at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com). In some cases, we won’t be able to guarantee complete access due to legal restrictions - for example, you will not be allowed to access files that contain information about other users or information that is confidential to us. We may not be able to fulfill requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort or would be extremely impractical.

  * You may update, correct, or delete some of your profile information or your preferences at any time by logging into your account on Classkick and accessing your account settings page. You may have to verify your identity before you can do that. You may also, at any time, update, correct, or delete certain personal information that you have provided to us by contacting us at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. Please note that while your changes may be reflected promptly in active content, users that have previously accessed the content may still have access to old copies cached on their device or may have copied and stored your content. In addition, we may retain a backup copy of the prior version for a limited period of time or for legal purposes.

  * Take a look at our “Parental Choices” section to see how you can obtain copies of your child’s personal information.

### How can I delete my account?

If you ever want to delete your account (or your child’s account, if you are his or her parent or guardian), you can do that at any time by contacting us at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com).

When you delete your account, we delete your profile information and any other content you provide in your profile (such as your name, username, password, and email address) and feedback and information collected through the mobile permissions you’ve granted. Information that you have shared with others, others have shared about you, or content other users may have copied and stored, is not part of your account and may not be deleted when you delete your account.

### How long does Classkick keep information about me?

We store your personal information for as long as it is necessary to provide products and Services to you and others, including those described above. Personal information associated with your account will be kept until your account is deleted, unless we no longer need the data to provide products and services, in which case we will delete prior to you deleting your account.

Please note that we may have to retain some information after your account is closed, to comply with legal obligations, to protect the safety and security of our community or our Service, or to prevent abuse of our Terms. You can, of course, delete your account at any time.

### What communications will I receive from Classkick?

If you registered on Classkick, provided an email to us, or otherwise opted-in to receive communications from us, we may send you messages and updates regarding your account, including privacy and security notices, updates regarding the Service, and information regarding products, features or services from Classkick. These communications may include, but are not limited to, social media updates, push notifications, email, and postal mail. If you have an account with us, we’ll also use your email address to contact you for customer service purposes, or for any legal matters that arise in the course of business.

If you invite another person to join you on Classkick by providing their email address, we may contact them regarding the Service using the appropriate form of communication. If they would prefer not to receive our communications, they may opt-out by by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any Classkick email, or sending an email to [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com). 

We may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us if your device supports it. We use this confirmation to help us understand which emails are most interesting and helpful. You can always unsubscribe from receiving any of our email or other communications whenever you’d like by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any Classkick email, by turning off push notifications on your device, or sending an email to [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com). Please note that if you do not want to receive legal notices from us, such as this Privacy Policy, those legal notices will still govern your use of the Website, and you are responsible for reviewing those legal notices for changes.

### Social Media Features/Widgets

The Service may now or in the future include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, and the Twitter Tweet button. These social media features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these social media features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing each social media feature.

### What if I’m not in the U.S.?

Classkick is hosted in the United States. If you use the Service from the European Union, or any other region with laws governing data collection, protection and use that may differ from United States law, please note that you may be transferring your personal information outside of those jurisdictions to the United States. By using the Service, you consent to this, and to the use and storage of personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### How can I contact Classkick with questions?

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or how we protect our community, please contact us at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com) \- we'd love to help. If you’d like, you may also write to us at:  
Classkick  
2545 W. Diversey, Suite 216  
Chicago, IL 60647  
Attention: Chief Privacy Officer

### How will Classkick notify me of changes to this policy?

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy - you can see when the last update was by looking at the “Last Updated” date at the bottom of this page. If we make any significant changes, we’ll provide a notice of those changes so you can review and make sure you know about them. We may post a notice on the Classkick Website, notify you by email (using the email address you provided), and/or alert you upon logging into the app.

In addition, if we ever make significant changes to the types of personal information we collect from children, or how we use it, we will notify teachers in order to obtain parental consent or notice for those new practices.

We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time, to stay informed about our collection, use, and disclosure of personal information through the Service. If you don’t agree with any changes to the Privacy Policy, you may terminate your account. By continuing to use the Service after the revised Privacy Policy has become effective, you acknowledge that you accept and agree to the current version of the Privacy Policy.

Last Updated: February 22nd, 2017

### What is FERPA? 

The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ([FERPA](https://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html)) protects the privacy of student education records. It requires schools to have written permission from parents, guardians, or eligible students before releasing any information from a student's education record. Without that written consent, FERPA only allows a school to share student information if an exception is met. The two most common exceptions specified by FERPA are: the “Directory Information” and “School Official” exceptions. 

### Is anything on Classkick an “Educational Record”? 

FERPA isn’t clear about whether the work completed in Classkick would legally be considered an Educational Record (see “[What Is An Education Record?](http://familypolicy.ed.gov/faq-page?src=ferpa#t52n214)”). So, it is really up to each school to decide if it is. If work completed in Classkick is deemed to be an “Educational Record,” then one of the exceptions must be met, or parent consent must be obtained. Our [Terms of Service](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service) are written to make it easy for schools to support either approach, and to thereby stay FERPA compliant.

### How does Classkick help schools stay FERPA-compliant?

Under FERPA, schools can use the “School Official” exception to share some information with third-parties that provide a legitimate educational function (see “[Who is a ‘school-official’ under FERPA](http://familypolicy.ed.gov/content/who-%E2%80%9Cschool-official%E2%80%9D-under-ferpa)”). Classkick’s [Terms of Service](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service) are written to support this approach. 

Alternatively, some schools or districts may instead choose not to rely on the “School Official” exemption, and instead get parent consent for each technology they use (see Parental Consent Letter). Classkick’s [Terms of Service](http://classkick.com/terms-of-service) support this approach, too, for complying with FERPA. 

Finally, our policies also confirm that that no student information will be shared with any other third-parties unless they aid in providing the Classkick service. 

### For additional questions

please email Classkick at [support@classkick.com](mailto:support@classkick.com)
